# Ryan Cole

+420 725 649 938

ryan@askdesigners.eu linkedin.com/in/ryancoledesigner behance.net/ryancoledesigner Vlastina 11 Prague 6, Czech Republic, 16100

## Designer and Developer

Highly creative and motivated designer and web developer with 10 years experience in the creative field in a large number of industries. Traditionally educated in design, and self taught in web development. A unique combination of design thinking and technical problem solving. Solid history of effective team working and collaborative success. High aspirations in projects and a keen eye for detail.

# Expertise

Highly effective team working Interaction design Public speaking and teaching

Big picture thinking Design thinking to solve real world problems Concept driven design

Communication Branding Frontend web development Designing with motion

# Experience

2015 - Present Fit Analytics - Frontend Developer (Berlin-Remote)

As a frontend developer, work on client integrations, new features, and bug fixes as part of the frontend team in Prague.

2014 - Present Brunchworks Podcast and Workshops - Partner (Prague)

In partnership with Marie Doucet, aimed at bringing Design thinking to non-design professionals and cultivate an understanding of the design process outside of the field. <u>brunchworks.co</u>

### 2012 – 14 Prague College – Digital Platforms Coordinator (Prague)

Worked with internal teams to execute digital projects within the college. Worked to unify areas of system and message overlap and recommend changes. Initiated and lead a project (Sylo) to build an internal student submission system to replace an old CD-based archiving process. Initiated a project to create a school-wide network of blogs used for course resources and inter-departmental collaboration. Initiated a program between the design and computing schools to allow students from the departments to meet and collaborate on projects. Assisted and advised the design department to move all record keeping to a cloud solution (Google Drive), resulting in a much more fluid operational model.

#### 2009 - Present Ask designers - Partner (Prague)

As partner at Ask designers, participate in all aspects of the business from client acquisition and management, project management, design and production. Clients ranged from small independent business owners and non-profits, to the CTK, a large state news agency. The primary focus was branding, extending to all media from print to digital, and included art direction, brand identity, and web design. <u>Askdesigners.eu</u>

#### 2009 - Present Prague College - Associate Lecturer (Prague)

As associated lecturer, designed and delivered course content for 7 HND Modules, 2 Foundation modules, and was tutor in 3 BA level modules. Topics taught include Interaction design, User research, Motion design, Packaging, Design to influence human behavior, Typographic poster design, Ideas generation, Introduction to design thinking, and Coding for the web. Lead students in live projects for real clients.

#### 2008 Lava Graphic Designers - Intern (Amsterdam)

As intern at Lava, was 1/2 of the Impakt festival team. Under the direction of a senior designer, created most of the final graphic work for the festival.

#### 2007 - 08 PHX Creative Communication - Intern/Freelance (Amsterdam)

As intern at PHX, worked on various internal projects including a redesign of the studio's webpage, and print material for ING Bank.

### Achievements

- → Participant in Fort Worth Sister Cities International Leadership Program.
- → "Richard Willstatter" Poster and "Kalamazoo Air Zoo" Campaign accepted into DSVC Student Awards Show.
- → Included in top 7 designers in graduating class of 45.
- → Impakt Festival (done at Lava) included in top 4 finalists for the Dutch Design Awards under the category of illustration.
- → Founded Ask designers Brand Studio with Markéta Klemesova, and acquired 13 clients in the first year.
- → Impakt Festival wins a Gold Award at the European Design Awards.
- → Started and ran a successful branding studio for a wide range of clients both locally and abroad.
- → Won account for CTK Photobank, the Czech national news agency's photography archive.
- → Successfully introduced new systems to Prague College, resulting in major improvements in teacher participation, efficiency, and quality.

### Education

2003-07

University of North Texas - Bachelor of Fine Art (BFA)

### Skills

#### Design

Concept Development Interaction Design User Experience User Research and Testing Information Design Information Architecture Motion Design Print Branding Copywriting Illustration

#### Software

Sketch Balsamiq Illustrator Photoshop InDesign Ableton Live Reaper Google Docs
Final Cut Pro Mac OS X Pure Data Sublime Text 2 Unix Command Line

#### Technical

HTML CSS Javascript Git MongoDB Node.js Angular 1.x Polymer Async Lodash

JQuery Coffeescript HTTP Audio Recording Motion Design

#### Other